<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <description>This is my personal blog where I explain all the  ridiculously nerdy things about my life.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I&#39;ll go  through my coding of iOS apps, tweaks, and websites,  along with a bunch of random stuff!
</description>
    <link>https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 12:50:08 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 12:50:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Coding Life - Part 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We left off at the BigBoss repository right? Well that’s a good topic anyways. I started submitting tweaks, and they started off pretty bad. Some were basically examples off of GitHub, but they got progressively better. I learned new ways to enhance my tweaks, and became a little better everyday. The thing is, there’s no guide or tutorial when developing tweaks. You learn from open-source code or on your own. I bookmarked thousands of open-sourced tweaks so I could learn a little bit, and my tweaks grew along with the knowledge. &lt;a href=&quot;http://moreinfo.thebigboss.org/moreinfo/depiction.php?file=simplencDp&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SimpleNC&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (although free) was my first big hitter, with over 100,000 downloads. I was just completely blown away at its success. That success drove me to create new tweaks, and paid ones. I was tempted to see if I could code the things I love and make money off of it. I made a couple paid tweaks and amassed probably around 2K. Then I met a friend online, and we began to talk about creating a tweak (eventually called &lt;a href=&quot;http://moreinfo.thebigboss.org/moreinfo/depiction.php?file=andriosDp&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Andrios&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) that would mimic the Android UI on a jailbroken iPhone. It started slow, but eventually steam-rolled into something much bigger. We got a massive following on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/logandev22&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/loganoco22&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and the hype for our project grew in the jailbroken community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were excited for our release and worked tirelessly for around 2-3 months everyday to polish everything and squeeze all the bugs out. It took on a life of its own, and I’ll never forget being a part of it. Finally, we released it when the hype was at a peak, and the result was incredible. The project made a combined 12K, and we split the profits down the middle as we handled all of the work ourselves, from the icons to the advertising and the like. 6K was now in my pocket, and I was in love with coding more than ever. The community had loved the tweak in its entirety, and I had never been more happy. It was a surreal feeling knowing that I could make something and have it make such an impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly followed Andrios with more and more tweaks, and I ended up wracking up around a total of 11K in jailbroken development money. With that, I was able to buy a very nice used car and I have never been more proud of something. I was licsensed this weekend and will be taking it to school on my own for the first time tomorrow. The entire experience was incredible and I will never forget the great reception the jailbreak community gave me as a new developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that phase over and the jailbreak in a lull for the moment, I have moved onto other things. I’ve made two iOS apps recently, and have been fiddling around with more web-based development. iOS is always where my heart will be, as nothing has made me feel so accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s my story in a nutshell. If you’d like to visit my GitHub and check out some of my jailbreak tweaks and iOS apps, go &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/loganoconnell&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;here&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. All my tweaks can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://apt.thebigboss.org/developer-packages.php?name=SimpleNC&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;BigBoss repo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 10:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2016/05/26/my-coding-life-part-3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2016/05/26/my-coding-life-part-3.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Coding Life - Part 2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2016/04/12/my-first-blog-post.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I went into detail of how I had made the transition from having no coding background up until the creation of my first app. Today, I’ll go from there up to the present. Here we go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That first app “Declutter” was amazing to me, but it wasn’t exactly the most fine-tuned app. There were issues, and I hacked my way around them in the app. Still, it was a working app, and I was very proud of my work. I purchased the Apple Developer membership and read online tutorials until I managed to get my app uploaded and submitted. It passed, and was uploaded on the App Store. The amount of pride I had in that was crazy. I loved the process and everything that it brought, I fell in love with it. “Declutter” was bought by my family and friends (I had put it up for $0.99, and eventually made it free), and although I didn’t make much money, I was not discouraged. The entire experience of uploading an app was worth much more to me than the couple of bucks I made from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One prominant issue on release of the app was I had targetted iOS 7 and up, but I had somehow forgotten to remove my linkage of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Metal&lt;/code&gt; framework. The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Metal&lt;/code&gt; framework was only for devices running iOS 8 and up, which created a problem. Users who were on iOS 7 (which was most of the population at this point in time) recieved a crash when launching the app because I was linking a framework that was not available on their device. My mom’s friend actually found this out for me, and I submitted a patch as quickly as possible. This situation helped me learn the importance of testing all possible case scenarios, and I understood what I had to do the next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, I became a little lost. I dabbled in a few things, but I left coding alive but on the back burner for a little bit. I made an iOS game based on one the kids in my school liked, and that turned out well but wasn’t appoved by the App Store for copyright reasons. I had also begun to get more into web design, and I taught myself that language before furthering my knowledge in a web design class at my high school. I became extremely familiar with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;JS&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jQuery&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PHP&lt;/code&gt;. Teaching myself all these different languages was a challenge as well, and with the mental roadblock I was in with iOS development, this allowed me to expand my knowledge of the coding world. I created websites on my own and experimented with different jQuery methods to see what looked best. All this self-teaching took lots of documentation reading, and I began to understand how it all worked more and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my website knowledge coming together, I made a few sites and uploaded them to the web with a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/code&gt; account. It was free and ridiculously easy to do. You can see what I’ve done with this site at &lt;a href=&quot;https://loganoconnell.github.io&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;loganoconnell.github.io&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I’m proud of the websites I’ve made and the templates I’ve edited to create that website, and I think it’s easy to navigate if someone wants to look through my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once my addiction to web design began to fade, I turned back to iOS, but now in a new light. I had jailbroken my phone, and was fascinated with the inner workings of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Cydia&lt;/code&gt; (the jailbroken version of the App Store). I downloaded tons of tweaks and examined them, trying to figure out how they were made. Then I did some searching, and I found a tutorial of how to set up Theos, the jailbroken tweak development suite, at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://iphonedevwiki.net/index.php/Theos/Setup&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iPhoneDevWiki&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tweaks are written in a language called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Logos&lt;/code&gt;, which is a subset of Objective-C. It was a great place for me to test my development skills and have free reign to change anything. Because when you develop tweaks, you have the freedom to change every single little aspect of your iOS device, and there are no Apple-imposed restrictions. From the look of the icons on your home screen to the color of the status bar, nothing evades the power of tweak making. In another tutorial I’ll go in depth into how it actually works, but it’s amazing. Being able to load your own code into your phone and being able to change anything is awesome. I looked through tons of open-sourced tweaks and began to learn how a quality tweak was made (the jailbroken community is big on open-sourcing). I created tons of tweaks, and they did very well. You upload the tweaks to a “repository”, which holds a wealth of tweaks for people to download from Cydia. I uploaded them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://thebigboss.org/hosting-repository-cydia&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;BigBoss&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a well-known repository that holds the majority of tweaks in the community. I’ll go into depth of how that all turned out in the final installment of my life story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This post was continued in &lt;a href=&quot;https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2016/05/26/my-coding-life-part-3.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;part 3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 08:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2016/04/21/my-coding-life-part-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2016/04/21/my-coding-life-part-2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My First Blog Post - My Coding Life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So this is where it all begins! I’m excited about this whole thing. I got my blog all configured with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and am ready to go. Now where should I start? Maybe with a little background about me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I’m a 16 year-old who lives in the United States. I live in a great community, and currently am enrolled in my sophmore year of high school. It’s almost over, thank god. I play basketball, frisbee, and I lift on random days through the week. I’m an active person, always looking for the next adventure to take on. In my free time, I’m usually procrastinating, spending time with people I love, or coding. My friends (especially my girlfriend) and my family all hold a very special place in my heart. Seeing them each day means so much to me, and although I may take it all for granted at times, I always appreciate everything they’ve done for me. They all encourage me and support my odd hobbies and my weird knowledge, and it feels good knowing I have such a strong backing from my family and friends. My girlfriend knows I code, and she supports me more than anyone. She knows how weird I can be, and not many girls would have such a strong love for a guy that spends his free time making apps. Means a lot to have her by my side! So now let’s dive into the important subject, my loving of coding. I’ll tell you how it all started, what I’ve learned, and where I am now. It’s gonna be a looong ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, my parents got me my first programming book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Absolute-Beginners-Guide-Portable-Documents-ebook/dp/B003J2RFEK/ref=mt_kindle?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;me=&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The Absolute Beginner&#39;s Guide to C&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, for Christmas. At first, I read a couple chapters and then gave it up. It had some hard concepts to pick up as a 12 year-old! But a couple months later, sitting in 7th grade class after our standardized testing, I decided to give it a shot again. I had progressed in math just enough to enable me to read this book, and now I was hooked. I became sucked into this book, reading every page and doing every little miny challenge at the end of each chapter. I just loved everything about the idea of creating something through a text editor, and seeing my product come to life in front of me. The entire process of coding just intrigued me, especially how it challenged my brain so much. The problems stumped me sometimes, and that was my favorite. School always came naturally for me, and thus it was ridiculously boring, so coding became my escape. I could challenge myself whenever I wanted to and all I needed was a computer. I plowed through the C book, and made a few small programs in the old TextEdit application on my family’s 2010 iMac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, I preceded to move on to bigger and better things. In the start, I had always had my eyes focused on iOS development in the near future. I was given an iPhone also for Christmas the same year I got Beginner’s Guide to C, so it was a match made in heaven. I loved the fluent design of iOS, and how each app strictly followed guidelines. Making an iOS app was what I wanted to achieve that year, so I set myself that goal and asked my mom to buy me the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Objective-C-Programming-Ranch-Guide-Guides-ebook/dp/B005OR9ND4/ref=mt_kindle?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;me=&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Objective-C Programming: The Big Nerd Ranch Guide&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; book, as I had figured out that learning the Objective-C programming language was the next required step in fulfilling my goal. Just like the previous book, I tore through this one, even more amazed at the intricacy of coding with objects. You could manage classes, protocols, and many other structures with this language. The Big Nerd Ranch Guide taught me so well, and I relished every word in that book. With Xcode fired up and the command line running in the background, my feeling of giddiness began to I began to live and breathe this language, and came up with new challenges for myself once I had covered all the material in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diving into the Cocoa framework for iOS, I realized I may need a bit more help to get to my goal. I decided my best bet was to continue learning from the Big Nerd Ranch and buy the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/iOS-Programming-Ranch-Guide-Guides-ebook/dp/B00IG8TGZ8/ref=mt_kindle?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;me=&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iOS Programming: The Big Nerd Ranch Guide&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on my iPad Mini. Ever since I bought that iOS Programming book, my life was changed. I was opened up to the world of coding and became entranced in the technology. Following the first tutorial in the book, I created my first app. It was a todo list app called “Declutter”. From the moment that app was finished, I knew coding was what I wanted to do when I grew up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This post was continued in &lt;a href=&quot;https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2016/04/21/my-coding-life-part-2.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;part 2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 22:12:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2016/04/12/my-first-blog-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://loganoconnell.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2016/04/12/my-first-blog-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
